<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hive on Vitthal Mirji</title><link>https://vitthalmirji.com/tags/hive/</link><description>Recent content in Hive on Vitthal Mirji</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vitthalmirji.com/tags/hive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A look at Apache Hadoop in 2019</title><link>https://vitthalmirji.com/2019/07/a-look-at-apache-hadoop-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vitthalmirji.com/2019/07/a-look-at-apache-hadoop-in-2019/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at whether Apache Hadoop still a viable option in 2019, with Cloud driven data
processing an analytics on the rise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first started using the Apache Hadoop Ecosystem, things around the magic buzzwords of “Big Data” and “Machine
Learning” were quite different compared to what happened since. In this article, we will take a look at what happened
since and how it compares against powerful, managed Cloud providers in 2019.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Lakes: Some thoughts on Hadoop, Hive, HBase, and Spark</title><link>https://vitthalmirji.com/2017/11/data-lakes-some-thoughts-on-hadoop-hive-hbase-and-spark/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vitthalmirji.com/2017/11/data-lakes-some-thoughts-on-hadoop-hive-hbase-and-spark/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This article will talk about how organizations can make use of the wonderful thing that is commonly referred to as
“Data Lake” - what constitutes a Data Lake, how probably should (and shouldn’t) use it to gather insights and why
evaluating technologies is just as important as understanding your data.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When organizations talk about the need to utilize data as part of their IT and business strategy, they usually have
certain goals in mind. A common question usually boils down to “How can we make use of the data that we have available
within our organization?”&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>